http://www.e-outdoor.co.uk/privacy-notice.asp

Login Create Account
Basket (0)
0.00
Go to basket
Shipping:
0
Discount:
0
Total:
0
Men'sClothing AccessoriesBeltsGaitersGlovesHatsScarvesSocksSunglassesFootwearAccessoriesBootsSandalsShoesWelliesJacketsFabric CareFleeceGiletsInsulationSoftshellWaterproofWindproofLegwearBaselayersShortsTrousersWaterproof TrousersTopsBaselayersShirts & TopsMen'sHow to Choose a BackpackYour backpack can make or break a trip. Learn to compare between the myriad of different options with this guide.How to choose Hiking BootsFinding the rights boots is the difference between blisters and bliss. Read this guide to make sure you get the perfect pair.Women'sClothing AccessoriesBeltsGaitersGlovesHatsScarvesSocksSunglassesFootwearAccessoriesBootsSandalsShoesWelliesJacketsFabric CareFleeceGiletsInsulationSoftshellWaterproofWindproofLegwearBaselayersShortsTrousersWaterproof TrousersTopsBaselayersShirts & TopsWomen'sHow to choose a Rain JacketThere are many constructions, features and designs to consider when buying your rain jacket. Learn about them here.How to choose Insulated OuterwearCan't choose your insulated jacket? This guide will teach you about synthetic vs. down insulation and more.ActivitiesHikeClothing AccessoriesFootwearGearHealthcareJacketsLegwearPacksTopsCampCookingElectronicsFurnitureGearHealthcareLightingSleepingTentsRunAccessoriesClothingEquipmentFootwearSnowClothingFootwearGearGoogles & HelmetsJacketsTravelClothingClothing AccessoriesElectronicsGearHealthcareLuggageSleepingCountryBushcraftClothingClothing AccessoriesFootwearGearOtherClimbingMountaineeringActivitiesHow to hike eco-friendlyThe outdoors is about freedom - but there are still some dos and don'ts. Get an insight into the unwritten rules here.How to choose Hiking BootsFinding the rights boots is the difference between blisters and bliss. Read this guide to make sure you get the perfect pair.EquipmentElectronicsBags & CasesOtherWatches & SensorsPacks & BagsAccessoriesElectronicsLuggageOtherPacksOther GearDrinkingHammocksLightingSafetyEquipmentHow to layer outdoor clothing - The layering systemLayering clothes gives you the versatility to master any environment. Learn how to layer by reading this guide.How to choose Hiking BootsFinding the rights boots is the difference between blisters and bliss. Read this guide to make sure you get the perfect pair.BrandsClearanceGifts
E-Outdoor Privacy Notice
Privacy and Cookies
We keep all your personal data on a secure server and we comply with all applicable privacy regulations and consumer legislation.
Please see our cookies policy to learn more about what cookies we use, their nature, purpose and related usage of your personal data on e-outdoor.co.uk.
Introduction
This Privacy Notice explains in detail the types of personal data we may collect about you when you interact with us. It also explains how we’ll store and handle that data and keep it safe.
We want you to be fully informed about your rights and how we use your data. We hope the following sections will answer any questions you have but if not, please do get in touch with us.
It’s likely that we’ll need to update this Privacy Notice from time to time. We’ll notify you of any significant changes, but you’re welcome to come back and check it whenever you wish.
When you are using our websites, ExtremeGB Ltd is the data controller.
Explaining the legal framework
The law on data protection sets out a number of different reasons for which a company may collect and process your personal data, including:
Consent
In specific situations, we can collect and process your data with your consent.
For example, when you tick a box to confirm you wish to enter a competition or that you are over 18yrs old.
When collecting your personal data, we’ll always make clear to you which data is necessary in connection with a particular service.
Contractual obligations
In certain circumstances, we need your personal data to comply with our contractual obligations.
For example, if you order an item from us for home delivery, we’ll collect your address details to deliver your purchase, and pass them to our courier.
Legal compliance
If the law requires us to, we may need to collect and process your data.
For example, we can pass on details of people involved in fraud or other criminal activity to law enforcement.
Legitimate interest
In specific situations, we require your data to pursue our legitimate interests in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business and which does not materially impact your rights, freedom or interests.
For example, we will use your purchase history to send you or make available personalised offers.
We also combine the shopping history of many customers to identify trends and ensure we can keep up with demand, or develop new products/services.
We may also use your address details to send you direct marketing information by post, telling you about products and services that we think might interest you.
When do we collect your personal data?
When you visit any of our websites
When you make an online purchase and check out as a guest (in which case we just collect transaction-based data).
When you create an account with us.
When you engage with us on social media.
When you contact us with queries, complaints etc.
When you ask us to email you information about a product or service.
When you enter prize draws or competitions.
When you confirm agreement to terms and conditions.
When you confirm you are over 18 years old.
When you choose to complete any surveys we send you.
When you comment on or review our products and services.
When you’ve given a third party permission to share with us the information they hold about you.
We collect data from publicly-available sources (such as Land Registry) when you have given
your consent to share information or where the information is made public as a matter of law.
If you visit us our CCTV systems may record your image during your visit.
What sort of personal data do we collect?
If you have a web account with us: your name, gender, date of birth, billing/delivery address, orders and receipts, email and telephone number and an encrypted record of your login password.
Details of your interactions with us online by email or social media.
For example, we collect notes from our conversations with you, details of any complaints or comments you make, details of purchases you made, items viewed or added to your basket, gift list and wish list choices, voucher redemptions, brands you show interest in, web pages you visit and how and when you contact us.
Copies of documents you provide to prove your age or identity. This will include details of your full name, address and date of birth.
Details of your visits to our websites, and which site you came from to ours.
Payment card information.
Information gathered by the use of cookies in your web browser. Learn more about how we use cookies and similar technologies.
Personal details which help us to recommend items of interest.
For example, you might tell us your clothing size, which we’ll use to guide our suggested items.
We’ll only use your personal data collected for recommending items of interest and to tailor your shopping experience with us.
Your comments and product reviews.
To deliver the best possible web experience, we collect technical information about your internet connection and browser as well as the country and telephone code where your computer is located, the web pages viewed during your visit, the advertisements you clicked on, and any search terms you entered.
Your social media username, if you interact with us through those channels, to help us respond to your comments, questions or feedback.
Here’s how we’ll use your personal data and why:
To process any orders that you make by using our websites. If we don’t collect your personal data during checkout, we won’t be able to process your order and comply with our legal obligations.
For example, your details may need to be passed to a third party to supply or deliver the product or service that you ordered, and we will keep your details for a reasonable period afterwards in order to fulfil any contractual obligations such as refunds, guarantees and so on.
To respond to your queries, refund requests and complaints. Holding the information you sent enables us to respond. We may also keep a record of these to inform any future communication with us and to demonstrate how we communicated with you throughout. We do this on the basis of our contractual obligations to you, our legal obligations and our legitimate interests in providing you with the best service and understanding how we can improve our service based on your experience.
To protect our business and your account from fraud and other illegal activities. This includes using your personal data to maintain, update and safeguard your account. We’ll also monitor your browsing activity with us to quickly identify and resolve any problems and protect the integrity of our websites. We’ll do all of this as part of our legitimate interest.
For example, by checking your password when you login and using automated monitoring of IP addresses to identify possible fraudulent log-ins from unexpected locations.
To protect our customers, premises, assets and staff from crime, we operate CCTV systems which record images for security. We do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests.
To process payments and to prevent fraudulent transactions. We do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests. This also helps to protect our customers from fraud.
Developing products, services, applications and designs that attract and retain customers. Improving customer interaction with our sites.we will use your personal data, preferences and details of your transactions to keep you informed by email, web, text, telephone and through our contact centres about relevant products and services including tailored special offers, discounts, promotions, events, competitions and so on. We do this to help fulfil our legitimate interests of providing you with the best service we can provide.
Don’t forget, you are free to opt out of hearing from us by any of these channels at any time.
To send you communications required by law or which are necessary to inform you about our changes to the services we provide you. For example, updates to this Privacy Notice, product recall notices, and legally required information relating to your orders. These service messages will not include any promotional content and do not require prior consent when sent by email or text message. If we do not use your personal data for these purposes, we would be unable to comply with our legal obligations.
We’ll use data we hold about your favourite brands or products. We do so on the basis of your consent to place cookies or similar technology on your device.
For example, we might display a list of items you’ve recently looked at, or offer you recommendations based on your purchase history and any other data you’ve shared with us.
To administer any of our prize draws or competitions which you enter, based on your consent given at the time of entering.
To develop, test and improve the systems, services and products we provide to you. We’ll do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests.
For example, we’ll record your browser’s Session ID to help us understand more when you leave us online feedback about any problems you’re having
To comply with our contractual or legal obligations to share data with law enforcement.
For example, when a court order is submitted to share data with law enforcement agencies or a court of law
To send you survey and feedback requests to help improve our services. These messages will not include any promotional content and do not require prior consent when sent by email or text message. We have a legitimate interest to do so as this helps make our products or services more relevant to you.
Of course, you are free to opt out of receiving these requests from us at any time by updating your preferences in your online account.
How we protect your personal data
We treat all our data very securely and we take all reasonable steps to protect it.
We secure access to all transactional areas of our websites using ‘https’ technology.
Access to your personal data is password-protected, and sensitive data such as payment card information) is secured and tokenised to ensure it is protected.
We regularly monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks, and we carry out penetration testing to identify ways to further strengthen security.
How long will we keep your personal data?
Whenever we collect or process your personal data, we’ll only keep it for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected.
When you place an order, we’ll keep the personal data you give us for six years so we can comply with our legal and contractual obligations. For warranty and recall purposes we may keep data until the end of the warranty period.
At the end of that retention period, your data will be deleted completely or anonymised, so that it can be used for statistical analysis and business planning.
Who do we share your personal data with?
We sometimes share your personal data with trusted third parties. For example, delivery couriers, suppliers to handle complaints, for fraud management, to help us personalise our offers to you and so on.
Here’s the policy we apply to those organisations to keep your data safe and protect your privacy:
We provide only the information they need to perform their specific services.
They may only use your data for the exact purposes we specify.
If we stop using their services, any of your data held by them will either be deleted or rendered anonymous.
Examples of the kind of third parties we work with are:
IT companies who support our website and other business systems.
Operational companies such as delivery couriers.
Direct marketing companies who help us manage our electronic communications with you.
Google/Facebook/Twitter/Instagram to show you products that might interest you while you’re browsing the internet. This is based on either your marketing consent or your acceptance of cookies on our websites. See our Cookies section below for details.
We will only share data with third parties for their own purposes in very specific circumstances
With your consent, given at the time you supply your personal data, we may pass that data to a third party for their direct marketing purposes.
For example, if you enter a holiday competition and tick a box agreeing that the travel company can send you promotional information directly. Or if we run a joint event with a restaurant, and you agree to receive direct communications from them.
For fraud management, we may share information about fraudulent or potentially fraudulent activity in our premises or systems. This may include sharing data about individuals with law enforcement bodies.
We may also be required to disclose your personal data to the police or other enforcement, regulatory or Government body, in your country of origin or elsewhere, upon a valid request to do so. These requests are assessed on a case-by-case basis and take the privacy of our customers into consideration.
We may, from time to time, acquire other businesses or ours may be acquired and this may involve the transfer of
your personal data to the new owner or controlling party, under the terms of this Privacy Notice.
What are your rights over your personal data?
An overview of your different rights
You have the right to request:
Access to the personal data we hold about you, free of charge in most cases.
The correction of your personal data when incorrect, out of date or incomplete.
For example, when you withdraw consent, or object and we have no legitimate overriding interest, or once the purpose for which we hold the data has come to an end (such as the end of a warranty).
That we stop using your personal data for direct marketing (either through specific channels, or all channels).
That we stop any consent-based processing of your personal data after you withdraw that consent.
Review by a Director of any decision made based solely on automatic processing of your data (i.e. where no human has yet reviewed the outcome and criteria for the decision).
You have the right to request a copy of any information about you that The Company holds at any time, and also to have that information corrected if it is inaccurate. To ask for your information to be amended, please update your online account, or contact our Customer Services team.
If we choose not to action your request we will explain to you the reasons for our refusal.
Your right to withdraw consent
Whenever you have given us your consent to use your personal data, you have the right to change your mind at any time and withdraw that consent.
Where we rely on our legitimate interest
In cases where we are processing your personal data on the basis of our legitimate interest, you can ask us to stop for reasons connected to your individual situation. We must then do so unless we believe we have a legitimate overriding reason to continue processing your personal data.
Direct marketing
You have the right to stop the use of your personal data for direct marketing activity through all channels, or selected channels. We must always comply with your request.
Checking your identity
To protect the confidentiality of your information, we will ask you to verify your identity before proceeding with any request you make under this Privacy Notice. If you have authorised a third party to submit a request on your behalf, we will ask them to prove they have your permission to act.
How can you stop the use of your personal data for direct marketing?
There are several ways you can stop direct marketing communications from us:
Click the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any email communication that we send you. We will then stop any further marketing emails from that website.
Email us using the contact email on the home page of each website.
Please note that you may continue to receive communications for a short period after changing your preferences while our systems are fully updated.
Contacting the Regulator
If you feel that your data has not been handled correctly, or you are unhappy with our response to any requests you have made to us regarding the use of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.
You can contact them by calling 0303 123 1113. Or on their website at www.ico.org.uk
We want to give you the best service by using cookies. Carry on browsing if you’re happy with our Cookie Policy, or find out how to manage your cookies Confirm
